welcome back
since it has now been a long time since when we moved to our new base
I think it's a good idea to go pay a visit to the old one
and while doing some cleaning
we bumped into a bookshelf
making a particular book fall out of it
upon inspection
it looks like some ancient wizardry Tome we didn't knew we had
but it caught our attention
and out of curiosity
we wanted to try following some of its weird rituals
the first one consist of placing a rudimentary pen on a couple of tables
to merge those in a single table
the second one asks us to put a green tablecloth on another table
and now we are supposed to do some research on the bigger table
but it looks like we are not knowledgeable enough in the art of magic
so we made a lens capable of revealing us the nature of the things around us
and thus we start our magical research
to find out what the world around us is made out of
turns out that
basically everything is actually a combination of compounds of six primal aspects which compose all of the atoms
after an exhaustive research of all the peculiarities this world has to show us
we are finally ready to try and do some research
to better understand how things connect together
forming theories which we can use for our magic experiments
and now it is time to get all absorbed into our studies
to unlock all of the knowledge that a common folk can have
and doing all of that research made us quite hungry
so we gather some shrooms
and use our newly acquired magic powers to get a cauldron
we are going to make a nice stew out of wheat, stone and magic shrooms
and it looks like somez grew out of it
we decide to take those back to our base
and cultivate those
and to help the growth
we can use an ultimate time anomaly
once they are fully grown
we can harvest those to drop spores
that we can collect and convert into magic power with the help of our broom
we can use that magic power in our green clothed table to craft a proper magic wand
to do some better magic
this wand will carry twice the power of our old broom
which also means that we have to cultivate twice as many shrooms
since that is too annoying
we shall use that power to find a solution
we start by making a better magic table
one that can easily pull the crafting items from ae2
which we use to craft the tools for fixing our issues with Mana
also knows as Vis
now we only need a source of Vis
luckily
we can use all the coins we have stocked up to buy a node from the quest book
we free it from its container
and drop it inside its new containment glass
now
we slowly tame it into a nice usable source of power
which we can check with our new goggles
finally to use its power
we place a vis relay nearby
and connect it to our crafting table
and with that
we are getting free passive magic power
which we can use to craft a new collection of crystals
but to do things
we also need some salis mundus
which we can cook into balanced shards
and ignore the random purple fumes coming out of our cauldron
they are just a new decoration for our old base
and we also gather some Silverwood Trees
just a few logs
that was to craft some Alembics
which will go on top of our new essentia furnace
with that
we can break down anything into its essentia components
the essentia will be extracted by the alembic
which with the help of pipes will output into jars
this essentia can be used with phials in a crucible
but what we are going to do next
is something slightly bigger and more complex
infusion
after building a big altar
we place the required essentia nearby
then after placing the correct items on the pedestals
we can start the process
this is a really slow process
and we have to place a lot of stabilizer things
such as the quicksilver blocks on the flooring to stabilize the process
however
the best way of doing that is by using some help from our technology
by turning on our time anomaly
the process will finish before its animation even manages to complete
and our first infused thing
is something that will let our technology help even further with our magic things
we are indeed in the digital era
there is no longer need to use those barbaric phials to manage our essentia
we can use DG(digital) essentia
now we can easily manage huge amounts of essentia from our AE2 network
now we have to get rid of the barbaric crucible
to do so we craft an essentia provider
we place it next to an alchemical construct on top of a crucible
now we only have to input the finishing item
and select the recipe
and there we have our clean crucible management
the next thing we have to manage better is our vis
to do so we want a better wand
however to get the good ones
we are going to need some more on essentia
which is super annoying to get
or maybe not
we just have to catch a wisp
then turn it into a spawner and put it in our mob farm
that will give us all kinds of essentia always with extra auram
we also get auram with extra auram
after breaking down the essence into essentia
we can craft our new wand core
however
while that core will allow for higher vis capacity
we should also try to get a better discount on the usage
but caps are not enough
we shall get a machine
that will help us craft the materials for some dresses more appropriate for the occasion
and after some textile work
we managed to make a new set of fashionable clothing
however that was not enough
our wand carry is 120 vis
and even with our current discount
we need 120.1 for a better wand
we need better dresses
luckily
our magic book has a whole section dedicated only to shoes
but this is not a retail store book
we have to do some sketchy rituals
to get our new accessories
and sometimes stuff goes wrong
we had forgotten some of the required essentia
to fix that
we can make an infusion essentia provider
that thing will let our infusion process work with DG essentia
no more need for those ugly jars
and there we have a new pair of nice looking goggles
however those don't match well with our shoes
and after looking at the shoes section
we couldn't find anything that fits well with our new goggles
so we instead moved to the electro magic stuff
this is forbidden stuff that only VIPs can use
now that we are fashionable enough
we can get a better wand
which we quickly upgrade twice
but we are not satisfied yet
however
to make a better wand
we need to use a different path
or to dress better
however while we could do more cool electro magic tools
we should probably go into a proper magician outfit
but that requires us to do definitely too much research
luckily technology can help there too
we can craft a machine
that will use electricity and node power to complete researches for us
all we have to do is input a research
and take out the discovery
with that
we can now research everything we can click on
however
doing so much research is actually destroying the node this machine uses
so we have to go find and bring back home a bunch of new nodes to do more research
which might takes more time than manually doing said research
also the weak nodes we find in nature won't last much
thus
we shall find a way of artificially creating new nodes
we start by making an unattuned node matrix
then we feed it all the useless essentia we have lying around
finally we infuse it into a node
however
that process is starting to take up too much essentia
so we have to find a better way of melting items
and the large essentia smelter seems perfect for the job
however
we miss some of the knowledge required to craft it
that knowledge is in a weird page of the magic book
that just appeared out of nowhere
and everything inside it looks spooky and seems to be taboo
but we decide to follow those weird rituals
and join the cult
and we are offered a nice looking dark armor
but I sustain that the white one is better
and that caused an argument with the cult leader who didn't agree
so we proved our superiority
and then jailed him
until he gave us the secret book with all the taboo rituals
however the more we go down that taboo stuff
the more weird things start to happen around us
sometimes we are followed by spiders
others by Arshog
and other times we are followed by ourselves
this is probably caused by too much work
so we shall take a quick break in our new spa
after our quick break
it's time to go back to our studies
which keep getting more spooky
but we are now too deep in the rabbit hole
so the only way is forward
and the next task our books are telling us to do
is to create a black hole at one of the cursed altars
we had seen laying around on the map
following that path
we have reached the Dark Realm
and after wandering in this labyrinth for a while
we have found a weird door
luckily the key was lying in a room close by
with just a couple of old weak ghosts protecting it
and our magnet quickly grabbed it
with that key we can now open the ancient door
and what we find behind is someone who is capable to take some of our carbon tipped vanadium steel sharpened auto repair bolts
he also managed to make us hungry
and deal us some damage
so we turn on our quantum shield
while we look for some tasty food in our AE2 terminal that can work wirelessly up to this place
once we are well fed
we can take down that annoying bug
without even bothering to pick up a sword from our backpack
and he left us the thing we were missing for our upgraded essentia smelting
however since we have only one of these pearls
we shall plant it on an island where the air is fresh
then we speed up the growth with some time anomalies
and it looks like it's growing so fast
that our crop matron can't hydrate and fertilizer it fast enough
not even a UV crop manager can keep up with the hunger of our accelerated crop
and it was then that
the ghosts came to remind us to take a break from our farming
and have a nice bath
and we came back just in time to see our pearl bloom
and we use that to craft the missing piece for our essentia smelter
this crafting has some instability
so we add a bunch of blocks and decorations to our altar to increase the stability
and thus
we managed to keep the Runic matrix inside its area while we crafted the new machine
but that was just the controller
we need more parts
the rest of the structure requires about 20 more infusions
and since we are in the industrial age
we shall not do infusions like barbarians
Steve's factory manager can manage factories
I guess it can also manage ancient rituals
we could do a nice tutorial on how to set this thing up
but I think it does not fit properly in our adventure
so if you want a tutorial
remind me in the comments
anyways after a long trial and error session
we managed to get our infusion to work on a 2 second timer delay
which for the way this program is made
means one infusion every 4 seconds
but it's not even a complete setup
since we still have to manually manage essentia
even though there are better options
and we should also make sure the altar is stable enough
and that setup was good enough to complete our new essentia smelter
which works at a decent speed
but makes quite some flux
but we can upgrade it in many ways
until it satisfies us
now we just have to do a lot of clicking
and I think that might be giving us some warp
anyways once we are too annoyed by all the clicking
we can turn that thing into a node
that is going to take four times more essentia than what we threw in
meaning that even with a 256 speedup it will still take some time to complete
but at least in that phase we can just sit and watch
until we finally get a new node
which we shall use for research
that node is going to be used up quite fast
but I think it's still easier to make than manually doing all of these researches
also if we were to go slower
there might be ways to restore the node
and that is what was left after all that research
by the way
there's another way to make nodes with millions of aspects
but I don't know how it works
also I think the process we just did gave me a little bit of warp
so I think it is a good time to get a good cleaning
to do so
all we need is a pure tear
or maybe we can upgrade it into a passive accessory
that thing is going to slowly remove all of our warp
let's see how fast it is
and in half of a Minecraft day
it removed none of our permanent warp
and some of the normal one
since that thing was supposed to be faster when you have more warp
I guess it will take too much time
so let's just use it here
that gave us all sorts of effects for half an hour
tired of waiting with no idea of how much longer that would have lasted
we just decided to take the faster approach
and with our luck
a couple of withers spawned exactly on the last moment
luckily that didn't bother us
so we could safely retrieve our stuff
and go back to work
and now you might be wondering why we went through all of that
well
there are many quality of life things gated by Thaumcraft
the first one is that we need the essentia wireless terminal
to get the universal terminal
which will allow us to do a lot of AE2 interactions from anywhere
next with a rainbow cacti
we can craft the infinite spray can
also we can now craft hearth canisters
so that we can find out
what are the next colors for our health bar
finally some magical vanilla items require thaumcraft to be crafted
those items are required to some rituals
to activate an ancient sigil
and you may wonder why we are going through the siege for those ancient broken things
well the answer is simple
after so many years
we want to put an answer to one of the oldest philosophical questions
well the answer is simple
after so many years
we want to find a solution for one of the oldest mathematical questions
what does iron divided by diamond do
and it seems the answer is in Schrödinger cat
so what's the lesson today
yeah
always AE2 craft things while you mess around
欢迎回来！
乔迁新居已许久
何不予旧宅一访
在我们打扫的时候
不慎撞到了一个书架
而这让一本书从中掉出
经检查
看起来像是某本未知的古代魔法书
它引起了我们的注意
出于好奇
我们想试着进行书中的奇怪的仪式
首先是在书桌上放上一支普通的笔
来把桌子合并起来
然后是在另一张桌子上放一块绿色桌布
现在我们可以在更大的桌子上做些研究
但看起来我们的魔法技艺还不够
所以我们做了一个魔导透镜
用来揭示周围事物的本质
所以我们开始魔法研究
去探究世界之本源
事实证明
基本上所有物质都由原子化合
而原子由六大基本元素组合而成
在对这个世界的所有特殊性进行了详尽的调查之后
我们终于准备好进行一些研究
来更好地了解各个事物之间的联系
产生用于魔法研究的理论
现在是时候沉入学海了
来解锁一介凡人可获得的所有知识
做了这么多研究让我们饥肠辘辘
所以收集好一些蘑菇
用最近取得的魔法力量获得坩埚
我们用小麦、石头和魔法蘑菇做一道美味炖菜
看起来是做出了始源蘑菇
我们决定把它们带回基地
并且培养它们
想让它们长快点
我们可以利用世界加速器
一旦它们完全长大
收获它们会产生孢子
在法杖的帮助下
孢子将转化为魔力
我们用那些魔力
在奥数工作台上制作一根合适的魔杖
来施展更好的魔法
这根魔杖的容量是之前的两倍
这也意味着种两倍的蘑菇
这太烦人了
我们将利用法杖的力量找到解决办法
从制作更好的魔法桌开始
它可以直接从 AE 里拉取物品
我们用它来制作解决法力问题的工具
魔力也被称为 Vis
现在我们只需要解决各类 Vis 的来源
幸运地
我们可以使用囤积的所有硬币
从任务书中购买一个节点
我们把它从容器中释放出来
放入新的容器玻璃中
现在
慢慢地把它驯服成一个优秀的 Vis 来源
我们可以用新护目镜检查一下
要使用它的魔力
我们在附近放置一个 Vis 中继器
并将其连接到工作台
有了这个
我们正在获得免费的被动魔力
我们用它制作一系列魔晶
如果要真正做事
我们还需要一些世界盐
它可以被煮成平衡碎片
忽略从大锅里随机冒出来的紫色烟雾
它们只是我们旧基地的新装饰
我们还收集了一些银木
就几根木头
来制作一些蒸馏器
放在新的源质炉子上
有了那个
我们可以把任何东西分解成它的基本源质
源质将由蒸馏器提取
在管道的帮助下
输出到罐子里
可以把坩埚里的源质导入安瓿使用
但是我们接下来要做的
是更大更复杂一些的东西
注魔
建好大祭坛后
我们将所需的源质放在附近
在把正确的物品放在基座上后
便可以开始了
这是一个非常缓慢的过程
我们必须放置很多稳定物
例如地板上的水银块以稳定过程
然而
解决此问题的最佳方法是求助于科技
通过开启世界加速器
注魔过程在动画完成前就能结束
我们第一个注魔物
能让科技更进一步帮助我们
我们本就处于数字时代
不再需要使用那些野蛮的安瓿来管理源质
我们可以使用数字源质
现在可以轻松地在 AE 中管理大量源质了
现在我们要摆脱野蛮的坩埚
为此，我们制作了一个源质提供器
我们把它放在坩埚顶部的炼金术构造旁边
现在我们只需要输入完成物
并选择对应配方
这就是我们整洁的坩埚自动化
接下来我们优化 Vis
为此，我们需要一根更好的魔杖
然而，为了做一根
我们需要更多的源质
这太烦人了
并非
我们只要抓住一只精灵
把它变成刷怪蛋放在工业屠宰场里
那会产出全部种类的源质以及灵气
我们还获得了带有额外灵气的天域之华
将天域之华分解成源质后
我们可以制作新的杖芯
虽然说
此核心允许更高的 Vis 容量
但我们也要有高的减免
只有杖端是不够的
我们应该做一台机器
来做更合适魔法的服装的所需材料
在一些纺织工作之后
我们做出了一套新的时尚服装
然而，这还不够
我们法杖可携带 120 Vis
即使按照目前减免来算
也需要 120.1 的 Vis 来做更好的魔杖
我们需要更好的衣服
幸运地
我们的魔法书有一整节专门介绍鞋子
但这不是零售店的书
我们得做些粗糙的仪式
来获取我们的新配饰
有时事情会出错
我们忘记了一些必要的源质
想解决这个问题
我们可以做一个注魔供应器
这可以让注魔自动使用数字源质
不再需要那些丑陋的罐子了
我们做了一副新的漂亮的护目镜
但是这些和我们的鞋子不太相配
看了鞋子区后
我们找不到任何适合新护目镜的东西
所以我们改用电子魔法工具
这是只有贵宾才能使用的禁品
既然我们已经够时髦了
我们可以获得更好的魔杖了
我们很快升级了两次
但我们还不够满意
然而
做一根更好的魔杖
我们需要使用不同的路径
或者穿得更好
虽然我们可以做更多很酷的电子魔法工具
我们也许应该穿上正式的魔法师服装
但这需要做太多的研究
幸运的是，科技在这也能发挥作用
我们可以制造一台机器
它将使用电力和节点为我们完成研究
我们所要做的就是
输入一项研究笔记
然后取出发现
有了那个
我们可以研究所有可点击的内容
然而
做这么多研究实际上是在破坏这台机器使用的节点
所以我们必须找到并带回一堆新的节点做更多的研究
这可能比手动进行所述研究需要更多时间
我们在自然界中发现的弱节点也不会持续太久
因此
我们要找到人工创建节点的方法
我们先制作一个节点基体(未调制)
然后把所有没用的源质都喂给它
最后将其注魔成一个节点
不过
这个过程会使用太多的源质
所以我们必须找到更好的方法来融化物品
大型源质冶炼厂似乎非常适合这项工作
然而
我们遗漏了制作它所需的一些知识
这些知识在魔法书的奇怪一页里
凭空出现的那种
里面的一切看起来都很怪异，似乎是禁忌
但我们决定遵循那些奇怪的仪式
并加入邪教
我们得到了一件漂亮的深色盔甲
但我坚持认为白色的更好
这与持有反对意见的主教产生了争执
所以我们证明了自己的优越
然后把他关进监狱
直到他给我们一本关于所有禁忌仪式的秘籍
然而我们越是触碰禁忌
周围发生的怪事就越多
有时我们会被蜘蛛跟踪
有时是被 Arshog 跟踪
而有时也被自己跟踪
这很可能是工作太多造成的
所以我们要在新的水疗中心休息一下
短暂休息之后
是时候回去学习了
但学的内容却越来越诡异
我们现在陷得太深了
没有退路可言
禁书告诉我们的下一个任务是
在被诅咒的祭坛上制造一个黑洞
我们在地图上见过那些祭坛
沿着这条路走
我们到达黑暗领域
在这个迷宫里游荡了一会儿后
我们发现了一扇奇怪的门
幸运的是钥匙就在附近的房间里
只有几个虚弱的老鬼在保护它
我们的磁铁很快就抓住了它
有了这把钥匙
我们打开那扇古老的门
在门后发现了一个可以承受我们
碳十字弓发射的钒钢箭尖自动修复弩箭
的 BOSS
他还设法让我们陷入饥饿
对我们造成一些伤害
所以我们打开量子护盾
在跨纬度连接到此处的 AE 网络中寻找可口食物
一旦我们吃饱了
我们拿下这个烦人的害虫
甚至懒得从背包里掏出一把剑
他给我们留下了升级冶炼厂需要的材料
然而，由于我们只有一颗珍珠
我们将它种在一个空气清新的岛上
然后我们用一些世界加速器来加速增长
看起来它长得太快了
作物监管机无法足够快地给它补水和施肥
即使是 UV 作物管理器也跟不上加速后的作物
就在那时
鬼魂来提醒我们从种田中休息一下
好好洗个澡
我们回来的时候正好看到珍珠绽放
我们用它做出源质冶炼厂的缺失部分
这个配方有些不稳定
所以我们在祭坛上添加了一堆方块和装饰品来增加稳定性
因此
我们在制作新机器时设法将符文矩阵保持稳定
但那只是控制器
我们需要更多零件
剩下的部分需要再注魔 20 次
既然我们处在工业时代
不应该像野蛮人一样注魔
SFM 可以管理工厂
我猜它也能管理古代的仪式
我们可以做一个关于如何设置这东西的教程
但我认为这和我们的冒险不搭
所以如果你想要教程
在评论中提醒我
无论如何，经过长时间的试错
我们得到了 2 秒延迟的自动化注魔
出于自动化程序本身的限制
意味着每 4 秒注魔一次
但这甚至不是一个完整的自动化
因为我们仍然需要手动管理源质
即使有更好的源质供给选择
我们还要确保祭坛足够稳定
这个设置已经足够我们完成大型源质冶炼厂的制造了
它能以不错的速度工作
但会产生相当多的咒波
但我们可以通过多种方式升级它
直到我们满意为止
现在我们只需要做很多点击
我想这可能会给我们一些扭曲
不管怎样，一旦我们对点击感到厌烦
我们可以把它变成一个节点
这将多用四倍已投入的源质
这意味着即使有 256 倍加速
它仍然需要一些时间来完成注魔
但至少现在我们可以坐着看
直到做出一个新节点
我们将它用于研究
那个节点很快就会用完
但我认为它仍然比手动进行所有研究更容易
另外，如果我们用得慢一点
可能有办法恢复节点
这就是所有研究之后剩下的
顺便说一下
还有另一种方法可以使节点具有数百万要素
但我不知道怎么搞
另外，我认为刚刚的过程给了我们点扭曲
现在是大扫除的好时机
为此
我们只需要一滴纯净泪滴
或者我们可以将其升级为被动配饰
那东西会慢慢移除我们所有的扭曲
让我们看看它有多快
在半个 Minecraft 日里
它完全没有消除永久扭曲
消除了一些一般扭曲
当你有更多扭曲时，那东西应该更快
我猜这需要太多时间
所以让我们在这里使用它
它给我们带来了半个小时的各种效果
厌倦于不知道会持续多久的等待
我们决定采取更快的方法
运气真好
在最后一刻生成了一些凋零
幸运的是，它们并没有困扰我们
我们安全取回物品
然后回去工作
现在你可能想知道我们为什么要经历这一切
好吧
神秘限制了大量优质道具
第一个是源质无线终端
用于制造通用终端
这将允许我们从任何地方进行大量 AE 交互
接下来是彩虹仙人掌
我们可以制作无限喷漆罐
还可以制作心之容器
这样我们就可以找出
生命条的下一个颜色是什么
一些魔法相关的原版物品也需要神秘
某些仪式要求制作这些物品
用来激活一个古老的符印
你可能会想为什么我们要为那些古老的破碎的东西而经历围攻
答案很简单
过了这么多年
我们想回答一个最古老的哲学问题
答案很简单
过了这么多年
我们想为最古老的数学问题之一找到答案
用铁除以钻石能得到什么
答案似乎在薛定谔的猫身上
我们今天学的了什么？
是呀
再胡闹也要有 AE 帮我们兜底
（奥数合成终端）
（什么长难句）
（原计划没有翻译这个教程，想看的也在评论弹幕提醒我）
（这锭处于稳定和不稳定的叠加态上）